Guide to the Riverside Quartz Mine (Tuolumne County, Calif.) Records, 1863-1905
Department of Special Collections
Riverside Quartz Mine (Tuolumne County, Calif.) Records,
1863-1905
Special Collections M0071
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1975
Biography
Quartz mine located on the Stanislaus River in Tuolumne County, California.
Scope and Content
Legal documents, deeds, stock certificates, and by-laws pertaining to the Riverside Quartz Mine.
Access terms
Riverside Quartz Mine (Tuolumne County, Calif.); Lake, Delos; Mines and mineral resources--California; Deeds; Stock certificates
Container List
- Mine Papers 1860 -1863 (Folder 1)
  - DEED: Lyman Stearns to Alexander Keltz. re: Alice, Emily Quartz Claim (NR) 1860, March 26
  - DEED: G.T. Martin to Harden and Martin re: Alice and Emily (NR) 1860, April 12
  - DEED: G.T. Martin to Guy J. Wright re: Alice and Emily (1/17) 1860, June 11
  - DEED: G.T. Martin to William Condon re: A and E. (1/17) 1860, June 11
  - DEED: G.T. Martin to Rederick McKenzie re: A and E (1/17) 1860, June 11
  - DEED: H.O. Beatty to G.T. Martin re: A and E. (2/17) (NR) 1860, Dec. 6
  - DEED: J.D. Patterson, Sheriff to I.J. Taggart. re: A. and E. (12-26-60) 1861, Jan. 25
  - DEED: I.J. Taggert to Abraham Halsey re: A and E (ND) 1861, Jan. 25
  - DEED: G.J. Martin to C.H. Randau re: loan of $1,000 1861, Feb. 1
  - DEED: Roderick McKenzie to I.N. Wright re: 1.5/17 of "Telegraph Mill" 1861, June 11
  - DEED: William Condon to I.N. Wright re: 1.5/17 of 1861, June 11
  - DEED: G.T. Martin to I.N. Wright re: 8/17 Telegraph Quartz Mill 1861, Sept. 3
  - DEED: G.T. Martin to Alexander Keltz 1861, Dec. 2
  - RECORDER'S CERTIFICATE: W.T. Browne re: "Telegraph Mill" 1863, June 6
  - COUNTY CLERK'S CERTIFICATE: R.E. Gardiner re: "Telegraph Mill" 1863, July 6
  - DEED: Alexander Keltz to Isaac N. Wright re: "Telegraph Mill" 1863, July 6
  - DEED: George F. Wright to Isaac N. Wright re: "Telegraph Mill" 1863, July 6
  - NOTICE: E. Casserly to D. Lake re: "Telegraph Mill" held for payment with P.S. by DL re: transfer of 1/2 of the above to Charles Brown 1863, Aug. 11
  - DEED: Eugene Casserly to Riverside Qtz. Mining Co. re: 4/17 Alice and Emily (draft) 1863, July
  - DEED: Isaac N. Wright to Eugene Casserly re: 4/17 Alice and Emily (draft) 1863, July
  - BILLS OF SALE: Telegraph Mill 1861 - 1863
  - NOTICE: E. Casserly to Charles Bowman re: transfer of shares 1863, Aug. 11
  - CERTIFICATE: San Francisco Bulletin Co. re: advertisement 1863, Aug. 25
  - NOTICE: Transfer and deeds Alice and Emily 1863, Aug.
  - DEED: J.J. Franklin to Isaac N. Wright re: 1/17 Alice and Emily 1863, Aug. 11
  - NOTICE: I.N. Wright to Eugene Casserly re: enclosed deeds and court case (Taggart vs. Kyle) 1863, Sept. 18
  - DEED: Eugene Casserly to Riverside Quartz Mining re: Alice and Emily 1863, Sept. 30
  - DEED: I.N. Wright to Eugene Casserly re: 1/17 Alice and Emily, 1863, Oct. 3
  - POWER OF ATTY: Chas. Bownerto D. Davidson 1863, Oct. 12
  - DEED: Isaac N. Wright to Delos Lake 1863, Oct. 17
  - DEED: Delos Lake to Riverside Quartz Mining Company re: 1/17 Alice and Emily 1863, Oct. 17
  - BALLOTS: Annual Trustees Meeting 1863, Nov. 12
  - PROXY: C.J. Dempster to Delos Lake 1863, Nov. 12
- Mining Papers, 1864 - 1905 (Folder 2)
  - NOTE: Donohoe Booth and Co./ RQM Co. to Donald Davidson, Ec & DL 1864, Jan. 1
  - SALE OF STOCK: A.D. Daunes to David & Thos. William, Riverside Mine & Mill, 1871, July 22
  - AGREEMENT: A.D. Daunes and John L. Murphy re: Supt's position & stock transfer 1873, May 21
  - RESIGNATION: D. Davidson as Pres. RQM Co. 1873, Oct. 11
  - DEED: Green T. Martin to David Williams re: 2/17 Alice and Emily 1873, Dec. 10
  - BILL OF SALE: L.Gibson to RMQ Co. re: Bldgs., lumber, & loose property on Grant Claim, 1874, Jan. 3
  - NOTICE: A.N. Daunes, re: specific locatoin of RQM Co. Alice & Emily 1874, May 11
  - NOTICE: Location of Water Right 1874, May 11
  - TAX ASSESSMENT: Tuolomne Company, 1874, Dec. 17
  - AGREEMENT: David & Thos. Williams with Samuel Grove & Addison M. Starr 1882, Oct. 11
  - AGREEMENT MEMO: (copy) same as above 1884, Feb. 16
  - AGREEMENT: David Williams et al with D.B. Austin et al 1897, Feb. 1
  - AGREEMENT: John Reynolds & Thos Williams 1898, Oct. 20
  - AGREEMENT: RQM Co. with Alfred S. Williams 1902, Dec. 26
  - LETTER: JR Welch (attny) to AD Daunes re: mtg of stockholders, 1/24 procedure 1903, Jan. 23
  - NOTICE: of stockholders meeting 1903, Jan
  - NOTICE: change of Principle Place of Business of RQM Co. (Recorder, Clyde C. of S.F.) 1903, Feb. 16
  - LEGAL DOCUMENT: Superior Court of California Case #1235 Co. Tuolomne, Geo. B. Austin vs. RQM Co. Thos. Williams Frederick Plank. Satisfaction of settlement for plaintiff (J.T. Conkey) 1903, April
  - AGREEMENT: David & Thos. Williams and John F. Bluett & Thos. Bluett 1890, Sept. 19
  - AGREEMENT: David WIlliams et. al. with D.B. Austin et al 1897, Feb. 1
  - AGREEMENT: John Reynolds & Thos. Williams 1898, Oct. 20
  - AGREEMENT: RQM Co. with Alfred S. Williams 1902, Dec. 26
  - LETTER: JR Welch (atty) to AD Daunes re: mtg of stockholders, 1/24 procedure 1903, Jan. 23
  - NOTICE: of stockholders mtg. 1903, Jan.
  - NOTICE: change of Principle Place of Business of RQM Co. (Recorder Clyde C. of S.F. ) 1903, Feb. 16
  - LEGAL DOC: Superior Court of California, Case #1235 Co. Tuolomne, Geo. B. Austin vs. RQM Co. Thos. Williams, Frederick Plank. Satisfaction of settlement for plaintiff (J.T. Conkey) 1903, April
  - AGREEMENT: (draft) Mary E. Williams & Edwin H. Williams 1904, Oct.
  - FORFEITURE OF BOND: Chas. G. Grim to David & Thos. Williams (Apr. 02, 1898) 1904, Nov. 26
  - NOTICE OF RESOLUTION: Edwin HL Williams as agt. of RQM Co. to apply for U.S. patent. per: Alfred S. Williams, sect. 1905, Sept. 20
  - BY-LAWS: Riverside Quartz Mining Company n.d.
  - LIST OF STOCKHOLDERS n.d.
  - LIST OF STOCKHOLDERS n.d.
  - MAP: Riverside Mine and Mill n.d.
  - NOTICE: change of principle place of business (1903, Feb. 16) n.d.
  - COVER: n.d.